Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute Ukrainian Cylinder Collection, 1908-1930s
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series II: Sound Recordings
  - Song with hurdy-gurdy accompaniement Пісня у супроводi лiри Sung and played by an unidentified performer Song, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy) Song index number: 181.0 Cylinder index number: 1909
  - AFC 1992/005: SR29 Male, solo singing Мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 182.0 Cylinder index number: 5 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR29)
  - "Dvorianka" narration about dvorianka "Дворiянка," оповiдання про дворiянку у супроводi лiри Sung and played by Hrytsʹko Oblychenko Sung narration, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 183.0 Cylinder index number: 35/162
  - Duma about Kozak Holota дума про Козака Голоту Sung and played by Hrytsʹko Oblychenko Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy) Song index number: 183.1 Cylinder index number: 35/162
  - Untitled song, female group singing Пісня без назви, жiночий гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 184.0 Cylinder index number: 35/163
  - Untitled song, female group singing Пісня без назви, жiночий гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 184.1 Cylinder index number: 35/163
  - Untitled song, female group singing Пісня без назви, жiночий гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 184.2 Cylinder index number: 35/163
  - "I am a Young Daughter" "Я дочка молода" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 185.0 Cylinder index number: 35/164
  - "Da, My Head Hurts" "Да головка болить" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 185.1 Cylinder index number: 35/164
  - "Oh, What Do You Fear" "Ой щож боўться" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 185.2 Cylinder index number: 35/164
  - Song about Karmaluk and Ilʹko Lukashenko Пiсня про Кармалюка та Iлько Лукашенко, сольоспiв Sung by Varvara Iavdokha Lukashenko Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 186.0 Cylinder index number: 35/165 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR30)
  - Song about Karmaluk Пiсня про Кармалюка Sung by Varvara Iavdokha Lukashenko song solo voice, a cappella F Song index number: 186.1 Cylinder index number: 35/165
  - Untitled song, group singing Пісня без назви, гуртовий спiв Sung by Dokia Dymydenko Song, choir Song index number: 187.0 Cylinder index number: 35/167
  - Untitled song, group singing Пісня без назви, гуртовий спiв Sung by Dokia Dymydenko Song, choir Song index number: 187.1 Cylinder index number: 35/167
  - Untitled song for female solo Пісня без назви, сольоспів Sung by Dokia Dymydenko Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 187.2 Cylinder index number: 35/167
  - Untitled song for female solo Пісня без назви, сольоспів Sung by Dokia Dymydenko Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 187.3 Cylinder index number: 35/167
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 188.0 Cylinder index number: 35/168
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 188.1 Cylinder index number: 35/168
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 188.2 Cylinder index number: 35/168
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 188.3 Cylinder index number: 35/168
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 189.0 Cylinder index number: 35/171 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR31)
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 189.1 Cylinder index number: 35/171
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 189.2 Cylinder index number: 35/171
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 189.3 Cylinder index number: 35/171
  - Untitled song for male solo singing Пісня без назви, мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 189.4 Cylinder index number: 35/171
  - Untitled song, solo voice Пісня без назви: сольоспів Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 190.0 Cylinder index number: 35/178
  - Untitled song, group singing Пісня без назви: гуртовий спів Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 190.1 Cylinder index number: 35/178
  - Untitled song, solo voice Пісня без назви: сольоспів Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 190.2 Cylinder index number: 35/178
  - Untitled song, female group singing Пісня без назви, гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 191.0 Cylinder index number: 35/192
  - Untitled song, female group singing Пісня без назви, гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 191.1 Cylinder index number: 35/192
  - "High is the Moon" "Мiсяць високо" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 192.0 Cylinder index number: 35/193
  - "The Sun Set Beyond the Hill" "Сховалось сонце за горою" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 192.1 Cylinder index number: 35/193
  - "Where Do You Roam?" "Де Ти бродиш?" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 192.2 Cylinder index number: 35/193
  - Untitled song, female group singing Пісня без назви, жiночий гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song index number: 193.0Song, choir, female Cylinder index number: 35/249 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR32)
  - Untitled song, female group singing Пісня без назви, жiночий гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 193.1 Cylinder index number: 35/249
  - "Evening song" Вечорниця Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 193.2 Cylinder index number: 35/249
  - "Oh, Elderberry Tree" "Ой, Калина, Калиниця" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 193.3 Cylinder index number: 35/249
  - "Ah, I Sew, Embroider" "А я шию вишиваю" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 193.4 Cylinder index number: 35/249
  - Kolomejka, male group singing Коломейка, мужиський гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Kolomyika, choir, male Song index number: 194.0 Cylinder index number: 35/250
  - Kolomejka (continuation) Коломейка (продовження) Sung by unidentified performers Kolomyika, choir, male Song index number: 195.0 Cylinder index number: 35/251
  - "Oh, Green Oak" "Ой, дубе зелений" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 196.0 Cylinder index number: 35/254 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR33)
  - Kolomejka, with instrumental accompaniment коломейка у супроводi iнструментiв Sung and played by unidentified performers Kolomyika, voice, instrumental ensemble Song index number: 196.1 Cylinder index number: 35/254
  - Instrumental selection, wedding melody одна iнструментальна весiльна мелодiя Played by unidentified performers Instrumental, ensemble Song index number: 196.2 Cylinder index number: 35/254
  - "And the Sun Played" Ладкання "Та заграло та й сонечко" Sung by an unidentified performer Ritual song: wedding solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 197.0 Cylinder index number: 35/255
  - "Come Dear, Come," "Прийди любко, прийди" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 197.1 Cylinder index number: 35/255
  - "Oh, They Beat, Tortured," "Ой били, карували" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 197.2 Cylinder index number: 35/255
  - Ballad about Lypeia балада про Липея Sung by an unidentified performer Ballad, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 197.3 Cylinder index number: 35/255
  - "Are We Being Drafted?" "Цими йдем в Катунi" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 198.0 Cylinder index number: 35/256
  - "Oh, Come Out Moon" "Ой зiйди мiсяченьку" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 198.1 Cylinder index number: 35/256
  - Wedding melody Весільна пісня Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: wedding, choir, male/female Song index number: 198.2 Cylinder index number: 35/256
  - Wedding melody Весільна пісня Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: wedding, choir, male/female Song index number: 198.3 Cylinder index number: 35/256
  - Instrumental wedding melody: tsymbalum гра на цимбалах, весiльна мелодiя Played by unidentified performers Instrumental, tsymbaly (dulcimer) Song index number: 198.4 Cylinder index number: 35/256
  - Untitled song: female and male duet singing Пісня без назви: жiнка i мущина дует Sung by unidentified performers Song, voice, duet, male/female Song index number: 199.0 Cylinder index number: 11 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR34)
  - Untitled song: female and male duet singing Пісня без назви: жiнка i мущина дует Sung by unidentified performers Song, voice, duet, male/female Song index number: 199.1 Cylinder index number: 11
  - Wedding melody Гра на цимбалах, весiльнi мелодiя Sung and played by an unidentified performer Ritual: Wedding song, tsymbaly (dulcimer) Song index number: 200.0 Cylinder index number: 35/260
  - Wedding melody Гра на цимбалах, весiльнi мелодiя Sung and played by an unidentified performer Ritual: Wedding song, tsymbaly (dulcimer) Song index number: 200.1 Cylinder index number: 35/260
  - Kolomejka Коломийка Sung and played by an unidentified performer Ritual: Wedding Kolomyika, voice, tsymbaly Song index number: 200.2 Cylinder index number: 35/260
  - "Ivan, Ivan, Do Not Walk in the Garden" "Iване, Iване, не ходи городом" Sung by a unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 201.0 Cylinder index number: 35/261
  - Speech (narration) Говорений текст та одна пiсня Spoken by an unidentified performer Narration, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 202.0 Cylinder index number: 10 or 441
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 202.1 Cylinder index number: 10 or 441
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 203.0 Cylinder index number: 15 or 450 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR35)
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 203.1 Cylinder index number: 15 or 450
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 203.2 Cylinder index number: 15 or 450
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by Andrij Zarytsky Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 204.0 Cylinder index number: 17 or 452
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by Andrij Zarytsky Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 204.1 Cylinder index number: 17 or 452
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by Andrij Zarytsky Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 204.2 Cylinder index number: 17 or 452
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by Andrij Zarytsky Song index number: 204.3 Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Cylinder index number: 17 or 452
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 205.0 Cylinder index number: 23
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 205.1 Cylinder index number: 23
  - Untitled duma for bandura and voice Дума без назви у супроводi бандури Perepeliuk, Duma, voice, bandura, male Song index number: 206.0 Cylinder index number: 1/s/m (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR36)
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспi Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 207.0 Cylinder index number: s/m
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспi Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 207.1 Cylinder index number: s/m
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспi Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 207.2 Cylinder index number: s/m
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспi Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 207.3 Cylinder index number: s/m
  - "Beyond the Blue Sea" "За синеє море" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 208.0 Cylinder index number: s/m-o/a
  - "The Blooming Blackthorn Bush" "Зацвiв терен" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 208.1 Cylinder index number: s/m-o/a
  - "Oh, from beyond the Mountains" "Ой, за гiр, гiр" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 208.2 Cylinder index number: s/m-o/a
  - Untitled song: group singing Пісня без назви: гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: x Cylinder index number: 30 or 264
  - Untitled song: group singing Пісня без назви: гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 209.1 Cylinder index number: 30 or 264
  - Untitled song: group singing Пісня без назви: гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song. choir Song index number: 209.2 Cylinder index number: 30 or 264
  - Untitled song: group singing Пісня без назви: гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 209.3 Cylinder index number: 30 or 264
  - Instrumental selection iнструментальна Played by unidentified performers Instrumental, ensemble Song index number: 210.0 Cylinder index number: 35/253 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR37)
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song Song index number: 210.0 Cylinder index number: 35/253
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song Song index number: 210.1 Cylinder index number: 35/253
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song Song index number: 210.2 Cylinder index number: 35/253
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song Song index number: 210.3 Cylinder index number: 35/253
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song Song index number: 210.4 Cylinder index number: 35/253
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song Song index number: 210.5 Cylinder index number: 35/253
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song Song index number: 210.6 Cylinder index number: 35/253
  - Instrumental selections, wedding melodies Гра на iнструментах, весiльнi мелодiї Played by unidentified performers Instrumental, ensemble Song index number: 211.0 Cylinder index number: 35/259
  - Audio samples and announcements, 9 audiocassettes. (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR38-SR46)
- Series III: Graphic Images
  - Negatives, Project-Related: PH01-PH40, 38 black and white 35mm negatives; 2 color prints (31⁄2x5 in. and 4x6 in.). (Box-folder 2/23)
    Photos taken from Joseph Hickerson's trip to Ukraine, March 1994.
  - Negatives, Ethnography: PH41-PH47, 7 copy negatives (4x5 in.). (Box-folder 2/24)
    Blind bards and instruments.
  - Negatives, Ethnography: PH48-PH54, 7 copy negatives (4x5 in.).
    Weddings from 1956-1959, 1964. From the Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute Archives Collection of Ivan Prokopiv, Vol. 14-3, pp. 492-.
  - Negatives, Ethnography: PH55-PH64, 10 copy negatives (4x 5 in.).
    Ukrainian traditions, rituals, costumes, architecture, etc. From the collection of the Art Museum of Poltava, 1897-1907.
- Series IV: Moving Images
  - USIA: The television and film service (60 minutes). (Tape-id AFC 1992/001: MV01)
    1 videocassette (VHS), Raw footage used in "Window on America" (Show #89), which was aired on September 17, 1994. Produced by Slavko Nowytski.
  - USIA: "Window on America" (Show #89). (Tape-id AFC 1992/001: MV02)
    1 videocassette (VHS), Air date September 17, 1994. Produced by Slavko Nowytski.
- Series V: Electronic Media
  - Ukrainian Wax Cylinders notes and scripts for announcements, 3.5-inch computer disk. (Tape-id AFC 1992/001: CF01)
  - Ukrainian Wax Cylinders notes and scripts for announcements (backup), 3.5-inch computer disk. (Tape-id AFC 1992/001: CF02)
  - Excel spreadsheet of sound recording inventory, 3.5-inch computer disk. (Tape-id AFC 1992/001: CF03)
  - Excel spreadsheet of sound recordings inventory (backup), 3.5-inch computer disk. (Tape-id AFC 1992/001: CF04)
Appendix A: Performers
Dymydenko, Doki^a female singer
Hrishchenko, I~va female singer
Lukashenko, Varvara I^avdokha female singer
Lukashenko, Ilʹko male singer
Malynka, Marii^a female singer
Polukash, Did (Grandpa) male singer
Shevchenko, Hryhoryi~ male singer
Shevchenkova, Marii^a female singer
Sokhot^ska, Ms. female singer
Zryt^sʹkyi~, Andryi~ male singer
Bernat^skyi, Ivan hurdy-gurdy player [lirnyk]
Boi~ko, Kornylo flute player [sopilkar]
Dovhanʹ, Petro flute player [sopilkar]
Dovhanʹ, Vasylʹ flute player [sopilkar]
Honchar, Larion hurdy-gurdy player [lirnyk]
Khrystenko, Kobzar bandurist [banduryst]
Kolisnyk, Nestir hurdy-gurdy player [lirnyk]
Makar, Kobzar bandurist [banduryst]
Movchan, Ihor bandurist [banduryst]
Oblichenko, Hrytsʹko hurdy-gurdy player [lirnyk]
Perepeli^uk, Kobzar bandurist [banduryst]
Poklad, Nazar hurdy-gurdy player [lirnyk]
Popovych, Oleksii hurdy-gurdy player [lirnyk]
Semenyshyn, Ivan pipes player [dudar]
Veselyi, Salyvon hurdy-gurdy player [lirnyk]
Bandura
Cimbalom [Tsymbaly]
Drum
Flute [Sopilka or Dudna, hand-carved Ukrainian wooden flute]
Hurdy-gurdy [Lira]
Pipe (Musical instrument)
Kobza
Violin